# Steven Nijman

Email: stevennijman@gmail.com Phone: +31646692463 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/steven-nijman

<u>Desired field of work</u>: Aiming for a career in the field of **data science** and **statistics**. Interested in a multidisciplinary approach, working together with a multitude of clinical departments and epidemiological research groups.

## Research experience

# University Medical Center (UMC), Utrecht (PhD.)

Promoters: Prof. K.G.M. Moons, Prof. F.A. Asselbergs

Oct. 2018 – (current)

Daily supervisor: Dr. T.P.A Debray

Developing statistical methods to work with a multitude of clinical departments and improve current ways of handling missing data in the electronic patient record.

- Created a novel imputation model in which missing data was handled on an individual patient level.
- Organized and led meetings with the research team and external organizations.

# Academic Medical Center (AMC), Amsterdam (Master thesis)

Supervisors: Dr. Martijn Schut (ref)

Nov. 2017 – June 2018

Grade: 8.0

Employing statistical learning methodologies to unravel the mechanisms behind Hospital-Associated Disability (HAD).

- Worked with a large and noisy data set, together with the responsible geriatrics department.
- Reduced a high number of variables to a much lower number of relevant variables using **factor** analysis.
- Created a novel **prediction model** in which competing risk factors were combined.
- Organized meetings with the geriatric department to encourage collaboration

## EverywhereIM, Hilversum (Internship)

Supervisors: Prof Dr Marlies Schijven and MSc Riëtte Meijer

Jan. 2017

Employing Google Analytics to capture and visualize recorded data from medical applications.

- Created a methodology from scratch to extract meaningful data from Google Analytics.
- Trained others to utilize the created methodology and continue the work.
- Made several **representations of data** for specific medical applications.

## University of Amsterdam (UvA), Amsterdam (Master Thesis)

Supervisor: Dr. Frank Nack

Jan. 2015 – Aug. 2015

Grade: 7

Provoking awareness in through the introduction of elements of Brechtian theatre

- **Created an experiment** in which players experienced elements similar to Brechtian designed theatre.
- Created the elements and materials from scratch to set up experiment with success.

## Education

# University Medical Center, Utrecht, the Netherlands *Post-graduate master in Epidemiology*

Jan. 2019 - (current)

A master about applied research at the intersection of data and medicine. With courses about statistics, (classic) study design and quantitative analysis.

# Academic Medical Center, Amsterdam, the Netherlands Master in Medical Informatics GPA 7,43

Sep. 2016 - June 2018

Courses about data analysis, healthcare organization, processes and logistics, data driven decision making in medicine and scientific analysis and reporting. Fully taught in English.

University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, the Netherlands Master in Information Studies: Game Studies GPA 7.65

Sep. 2014 - Aug. 2015

Courses including interdisciplinary research methodology for information sciences, game technology, games in society, innovation and design thinking and mobile systems.

University of applied sciences Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands Bachelor in Communication and Media Design Graduation project grade: 8

Sep. 2009 - June 2013

Courses about communication, media design, project participation, user experience and creative thinking. Included the minor co-design studio and a specialization in visual design.

# Montessori Lyceum Herman Jordan, Zeist, the Netherlands *HAVO (NG)*

Sep. 2004 - June 2009

Included beta subjects such as chemistry, math and biology.

#### Skills and activities

### Software skills

- Skilled in **statistical learning** with R.
- Skilled in **multivariate analysis** with R.
- Skilled in **factor analysis** with R.
- Basic skill with C.

# Language skills

• Fluent Dutch and English (Level C2)

### Teaching experience

NOC\*NSF certified Nunchaku teacher (2018)

### Extra- curricular activities

- Deep learning reading group, reading through: "Deep-learning book" (2019)
- Study and career program, identifying personality, values and skills (2018)
- Self-employed at Thatchy, offering consultancy to medical organizations (2017-2018)
- Minor programming, followed an evening programming course (2017)

### Other related skills

- Experience working with complex and unintuitive data sets
- Experience working in multidisciplinary setting

# References

Martijn Schut, PhD, AMC Supervisor Master Thesis m.c.schut@amc.nl, +31653161830